20 Days in Mariupol is a documentary, war film directed by Mstyslav Chernov.
As the Russian invasion begins, a team of Ukrainian journalists trapped in the besieged city
of Mariupol struggle to continue their work documenting the war's atrocities.
Self - Narrator and Interviewer, played by Mstyslav Chernov.
Self, played by Evgeniy Maloletka.
Self, played by Liudmyla Amelkina.
Self, played by Zhanna Homa.
Self, played by Oleksandr Ivanov.
Self, played by Irina Kalinina.
20 Days in Mariupol (Ukrainian: «20 днів у Маріуполі», romanized: 20 dniv u Mariupoli) is a 2023 Ukrainian documentary film
with footage from the first several weeks of the Russian invasion of Ukraine directed by Mstyslav Chernov.
The film had its world premiere at the 2023 Sundance Film Festival, where
it won the Sundance World Cinema Documentary Competition.
It was selected as the Ukrainian submission for the Academy Award for Best International Feature Film at the 96th Academy
Awards, but it was instead nominated in the Best Documentary Feature Film category and went on to win the award.
The film was also nominated for two BAFTAs and won one of them, also won a Directors
Guild of America Award and Ukrainian National Film Academy Award.
The film has received critical acclaim and was named one of the top five
documentary films of 2023 by the National Board of Review.
The film was also screened at the start of the 78th
session of the UN General Assembly.
The film explores themes of casualty of war, mourning, vladimir
putin, angry, russian invasion of ukraine (2022).